Register of the Colombian Subject Collection, 1914-2000
Hoover Institution Archives
Colombian Subject Collection,
1914-2000
XX803
1 manuscript box (.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, election campaign literature, studies, and speeches, relating primarily to political conditions and elections in Colombia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Colombia--Politics and government.; Elections--Colombia.; Colombia.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1992 (Box 1)
  Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, handbills, manifestoes, open letters, campaign literature, note, bulletin, statement, communique and currency, principally relating to political, economic and social conditions. Includes material from political parties and guerrilla movements
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been added since December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1992
  - General. Serial issues, political flyers, commercial handbills, clipping, bibliography, program, announcement, speech, currency (bill with political slogan), mainly relating to political, economic and social conditions, 1965-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Elections
    - 1949. Campaign literature, posters, manifestoes, leaflets, open letters, statement and explanatory note. Includes evidence of official interference in electoral process, as well as documentation of secret police activities (Folder 2)
    - 1990. Reports produced by American analysts, 1990. In English (Folder 3)
  - Guerrilla movements. Serial issues and communique, 1982-1987. Includes material from the Union Camilista - Ejercito de Liberacion Nacional, the Ejercito Popular de Liberacion and the Movimiento 19 de Abril (M-19), as well as a joint declaration by the M-19 and the Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Colombia (FARC) (Folder 4)
  - Political parties and movements. Serial issues and leaflet, 1965-1988. Includes material from the Partido Comunista de Colombia and the Nuevo Liberalismo and Rojismo movements (Folder 5)
  - Student movements and universities. Bulletin and leaflets, 1964 (Folder 6)
  - Trade unions. Serial issues, 1957-1965. Includes material from the Union de Trabajadores de Colombia (UTC) (Folder 7)
  - World War, 1914-1918. Copy of a document describing radio broadcasts during wartime, including a discussion of censorship restrictions, 1914 (Folder 8)